TONG TSUI KEUN MARY ANN

No. 40, Jalan Prima 3/3, Taman Puchong Prima, 47150 Puchong, Selangor Darul Ehsan, Malaysia Mobile: +6012-292 6293 ● tong.maryann@gmail.com

PERFORMANCE PROFILE

I am a dedicated and extremely motivated administrative professional with a long-standing successful career encompassing diverse domestic and international experience throughout multiple industries and within various capacities.

I am deadline driven with outstanding organizational, interpersonal and multi-tasking skills. Being a fast learner with a strong ability to work independently aids my ability to adapt to new environments. I am familiar with all aspects of daily business operations covering but not limited to: Personnel, Human Resource Issues, Payroll, LHDN Tax Preparation and numerous administrative and finance functions. I am adept in bookkeeping, cash flow management and the efficient running of an office's operations.

Being an extremely reliable individual with strong business values and a tenancy to continuously improve by challenging the status quo, I believe I can be an asset to your business.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Bookkeeping & Finance
- Human Resources
- Payroll
- Accounts Payable & Receivable
- Filing & Organization
- Negotiating
- Planning

- Written & Verbal Communications
- Event Management
- Presentation Skills
- Creativity & Solution Focussed
- Team Player
- Multi-tasking Expertise

Proficient in:

- Accounting, data and administrative management practices and procedures, legislative requirements
- Human resources management practices and procedures
- Business and management principles
- Computer skills and knowledge of office software packages

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Windows 7, MS Word, Excel, Outlook, Power Point, MYOB Payroll, SAP, Citrix – internal companies ERP system

PERFORMANCE HIGHLIGHTS

- Extensive experience collaborating with multiple departments including HR, finance, sales, marketing and IT on both a domestic and international level. Not limited to supplies and vendors related to the operations of the company.
- Over 10 years of experience working in high performance organisations.
- Recognised and appraised in providing variety of Director's support tasks that are highly confidential and sensitive.
- Recognized for my ability to build strong relationships and get the job done.
- Ability to negotiate appraised prices and document contracts with suppliers.
- Achieve financial objectives by anticipating requirements, preparing and submitting budget and proposals for overall operational improvements in productivity and efficiency.
- Manage procurement of office inventory, furniture, administrative supplies, shipping/warehouse equipment and company properties.
- A lateral thinker that is solution focussed and hence an ability to rapidly resolve complicated problems and avoid escalation.
- Managed a complete office relocation with minimal downtime.
- Superior event management skills, successfully planned, organised and execute a conference of 36 pax.
- Travel and conduct required site inspections for event venues.
- Recognised for expanded secretarial and administrative duties to a department of 170 headcounts in 2 locations but not limited to effective office management activities and maintain overall upkeep, efficiency and effectiveness of the department.
- Trained and improved department monthly submission of annual leave, replacement leave, medical leave, claims medical, entertainment, transportation, travel allowance, mobiles and etc according to company policy and procedures.
- First level of approval for all claims before the Director's.
- Developed and maintain proper filing system, safe keeping for all office files, correspondences, reports, projects, proposals and confidential documents and ensuring effective document control for easy access, retrieval & references.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Office Manager 2011 - 2014
HR & Admin Administrator 2011
Office Administrator 2010

COLEMAN BRANDS PTY LTD (Regional Office)

Personal Assistant

- Continued high quality personal and confidential support to the Country Manager/General Manager, arrange and coordinate business schedules/events and corporate functions, appointments and travel arrangements includes flights, visas, accommodation and incidentals.
- Arranging meetings and appointments, coupled with the organisation skills to coordinate complex travel itineraries.
- Managed local visa requirements.
- Provide full support to the Country Manager/General Manager and his family for all personal matters which includes family relocating to Malaysia. Home searching and requirements, insurances, banking, commuting arrangements and kids school enrolment.

- Time management. Organised and maintain diaries including making appointments, meetings and conferences for both personal and business related affairs or for key deliverables and dates.
- General support and assistance during presentations, maintaining efficient data management and filing systems.
- Prepare confidential and official correspondences, memorandum, agenda and minutes of meeting. Carrying out specific projects and research as and when required.
- Manage all office requirements and an efficient document handling system.
- Perform other duties as assigned and directed by Country Manager/General Manager.
- Manage all travel arrangements, accommodation and meetings/appointments for the Asia Pacific Finance Director's quarterly visits to Asia Pacific (based in Australia).
- Screen all calls and appointments for efficient use of Country Manager/General Managers time.
- Monthly Amex Card coding, matching and processing of the Country Managers company expense card as directed by the Asia Pacific Finance Director.

Office Manager

- Developed and implemented professional business practices and management to organise all aspects of an efficient and secure office operation.
- Researched and submitted formal proposals for the purchase of computer equipment, mobile phones and appropriate software to meet financial and clerical needs.
- Nominated trainer for other staff members in all facets of computer applications.
- Office compliance & HR Management.
- Developed Standards and KPI's to manage processes, facilitate supervision and promote process improvement whilst embracing a continuous improvement environment.
- Maintained office services by organizing office operations and procedures; preparing payroll; controlling correspondence; designing filing systems; reviewing and approving supply requisitions; assigning and monitoring clerical functions.
- Maintained office efficiency by planning and implementing office systems, layouts, and equipment procurement.
- Maintained professional and technical knowledge by attending hotel events; reviewing professional publications; establishing personal networks; participating in professional societies.
- Achieved financial objectives by preparing an annual budget; scheduling expenditures; analyzing variances; initiating corrective actions when and if required.
- Provide effective communications and relationships with internal and external contacks, ensuring that messages and relations contribute positively to the Company's reputation and credibility.
- Ensure the Local Office adheres to and adopts all of Asia Pacific's Head Office requirements, security and internal controls.
- Efficiently planned and executed an office relocation.
- Facilitate the quarterly audit review of the local office by the Asia Pacific Finance Director. Document and execute any findings to ensure timely execution and internal compliance.
- Monthly Amex Card coding, matching and processing as directed by the Asia Pacific Finance Director.

Finance

- Monthly EOM, cash flow, forecast, accruals, budget, quarterly funds request from Australia.
- Reporting, record keeping and documentation of business deals, internal audits and budget control. Manage and track funding goals of credit analysis.

- Responsible for all accounting activities, including Accounts Receivable, Accounts Payable, General Ledger and Purchase Request procedures.
- Monthly KPI and variance analysis reporting to the Asia Pacific Finance Director.
- Petty Cash management.
- Employee Expense Reimbursement Control and management.
- General Ledger reconciliations and document control.
- Monthly, Quarterly and annual Forecasting.
- Support the Annual Planning process.
- Funds Request Report.
- Regional Office Registration with MIDA.
- Deloitte engagement in conjunction with the Asia Pacific Finance Director.
- Company bank account set-up, funds monitoring USD & MYR, reconciliations and FX transfer.
- Submission of Marketing Request Proposals.
- Develop all forms to aid Financial Internal Control.
- Monthly meeting with the Asia Pacific Finance Director on all administrative and office matters.
- Documentation and filing of TPOV's.
- Monthly MYOB reporting and file submission.

Human Resource

- Managed and attended to all queries & ensured compliance to company policies on Compensation & Benefits.
- Initiate employee benefits and setup of the Regional Office.
- Administered the timely processing of monthly payroll activities in a professional manner whilst ensuring accuracy and the effective communication to the Asia Pacific Finance Director. This includes timely submission of EPF, SOCSO and Income Tax to relevant parties.
- Work with tax consultant on expatriates' tax declaration prior to their departure, responsible
 for preparing year-end income tax reports for employees (both local employee and expatriate)
 and Liaise with statutory bodies on payroll related matters.
- Prepare payroll summary reports, annual leave and replacement leave for the Asia Pacific Finance Director's review.
- Administer and monitor employees' claim records to ensure policy adherence and accurate collation and recording.
- Ensure all payroll related transactions are properly charged to respective GL accounts.
- Handle queries relating to payroll administration and processing.
- Maintain proper records and filing of all HR documentation for easy retrieval and reference.
- Ensuring the employee payroll and ad-hoc payments are handled in an efficient, accurate and timely manner.
- Maintain confidentiality at all times and ensure secure record keeping.
- Manage MYOB Payroll module to ensure the accuracy of the system.
- Manage the Regional Office staff performance appraisal cycle to ensure adherence to head office's requirements is timely and accurate.

IT

- First level PC, printer, network support, office network, LAN, Wi-Fi, telecommunication and etc.
- Setup of PC, emails, mobile phones with IT Support based in China.
- Manage the local office security permissions for remote access to office files.
- Develop and manage the secure backup requirements of all electronic files.

Administrator – Secretary to the Director of RSSD Fujitsu (Malaysia) Sdn. Bhd.	2008 - 2010
Product Executive – Oracle & Citrix (PM) Jardine OneSolution (2001) Sdn Bhd (JOS Distribution)	2008
Business Unit Administrator – Specialty Care (Contract) Schering-Plough Sdn Bhd	2007 - 2008
Account Executive Corbis Images (Malaysia) Sdn. Bhd.	2007
Project Secretary (Contract) Lafarge Asia Sdn. Bhd. (Asia Technical Centre)	2006 - 2007
Operations Executive (Temporary) Connectway Logistics Sdn Bhd	2006
Senior Business Centre Administrator Personal Assistant to Managing Director Channels Executive SMT Smart Media Sdn Bhd @ Smart Central	2003 - 2006
Business Centre Administrator Personal Assistant to Managing Director SMT Smart Media Sdn Bhd @ Smart Central	2001 - 2003
Confidential Secretary to Managing Director Professional & Organisation Development Sdn Bhd	1997 - 2001
Junior Secretary, Reporting to Director and PA MudahJuta Industries Sdn Bhd	1997
EDUCATION	
Bachelor of Business Administration (Honours) Majoring in Marketing Help University College (University of East London)	2001 - 2005
Diploma in Administrative Management (IAM) Stamford College	1996
Diploma in Executive Secretarialship (DES) Stamford College	1996
Private Secretarial Course 1995 London Chamber of Commerce & Industry (LCCI) Typewriting – Second Level London Chamber of Commerce & Industry (LCCI) Manuscript Transcription – Third Level Stamford College, PJ	

Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM)

1994

Sekolah Menengah St. Bernadette's Convent, Batu Gajah, Perak

LANGUAGE

Spoken – English, Bahasa Malaysia, Cantonese, Mandarin Written – English and Bahasa Malaysia

REFERENCES

Available upon request